Salim Zubair

Mobile: (778) 302-4621 Website: https://salimzubair.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/salim-zubair/ Email: salim-zubair@yahoo.com

Profile

Multi-skilled data scientist with 2 years of professional experience discovering insights and building
machine learning applications to solve business problems. Experienced in natural language
processing/understanding, data processing, predictive modelling, information architecture and
business communication.

Skills

- Python
- SQL/ NoSQL
- Pandas/ Numpy / Scikit-learn/ Dask
- Spark/ Hadoop
- SpaCy/ NLTK
- Tableau
- Google Cloud Platform, Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services

- Machine Learning/ Deep Learning
- ETI
- Data Modelling
- Data Visualization
- Data Architecture
- Statistics
- Natural language processing/understanding
- Project Management

Education

Master of Information Science

2017- 2018

BSc Business Computing Systems 2013-2016

- University of British Columbia Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada
- University of Northampton Northampton, Northamptonshire, England

Work History

Consultant – Information Systems Analyst

July 2018 - Present

BC Hydro

Burnaby, British Columbia

- Built NLP machine learning solution to analyze, classify and tag 1.7 million corporate documents with appropriate descriptors and metadata tags
- Performed analysis of IT/Information management requirements
- Worked with project team to design and build GIS-enabled cloudbased enterprise document management system
- Wrote the information management policy to guide the BC Hydro Environment department

Graduate Teaching Assistant - Data Visualization

September 2017- January 2018 **University of British Columbia**

Vancouver, British Columbia

- Ran weekly workshops on data visualization and data analysis
- Presented lectures
- Supervised learning projects
- Assessed student progress and provided constructive feedback

Magento Developer

November 2015 – December 2015

stepnpump.com/

Northampton, England

- Designed and developed e-commerce platform for online retailer
- Restructured database as per client's needs